Daniel Wayne Burer

hire@danielburer.com

Summary

Experienced and active software developer with a demonstrated history of performance in the Information Technology industry. Skilled in software engineering, full-stack web development, and digital design. Currently pursuing a Master of Science in Computer Science at Georgia Tech.

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Master of Science in Computer Science, Major GPA 4.0

Atlanta, GA May 2021

Georgia Southern University

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Major GPA 4.0

Software Engineering Certificate

Game Programming Certificate

May 2018

Statesboro, GA

Relevant Coursework

• CSCI 5530 – Software Engineering

• CSCI 5431 – Computer Security

- CSCI 5331 Computer Architecture
- CSCI 5330 Algorithm Design and Analysis

Professional Work Experience

Morris Technology

Senior Solutions Developer

Statesboro, GA February 2018 - Present

- Full stack development of web-based Content Management System applications using JavaScript, React, HTML, Python, and the Django web framework
- Create, prototype, and implement responsive web design UI/UX for new features and the revision of outdated components
- Oversee regular production deployments, assist in coaching of part of part-time developers, and administrate team communication tools and development environment configuration
- Review, critique, and approve codebase modifications by team members before transfer of changes from development to production environments

Morris Technology

Statesboro, GA

Junior Solutions Developer

April 2016 - February 2018

- Full stack development of web-based Content Management System applications
- Implementation and production of responsive web design frameworks built with HTML and SCSS
- Cross-platform mobile app development using Ionic and AngularJS frameworks
- Collaboratively developed using Git version control and regularly unit test and integration test codebase
- Provided direct customer support to perform regular codebase maintenance and implement new features

Gulfstream Aerospace Corporation

Pooler, GA

SAP Basis Intern

January 2017 - August 2017

- Performed multiple simultaneous 2017 Enhancement Pack upgrades on Gulfstream production SAP systems, including both ABAP and Java stacks
- Participated in regular daily sustainment and administrative activities including SAP note implementation, component patching, and kernel upgrades
- Performed STMS transports/imports for both non-production and production SAP systems, reviewed logs for errors, and subsequently informed development teams with relevant results
- Assisted in the general workflow of Basis user problems and requests, accepting or dispatching to other Basis team members where appropriate

Core Qualifications

- Proficiency in a broad set of development, architecture, and administrative skills
- Well-versed in general information technology
- Extensive experience in professional communication and performing in a team environment

Relevant Skills

- Proficient in general-purpose software development with Java, Python, and C#.
- Extensive and comprehensive full-stack web development history using HTML5, JavaScript, CSS, Node.js, and associated frameworks/preprocessors including React, AngularJS, SASS, and Django.
- Skilled with a variety of other development languages and frameworks, including C, C++ and PHP.
- Familiar and capable with major database technologies including PostgreSQL and Microsoft SQL Server.
- Experienced in team software development environments, project coordination and distribution, modern version control and testing systems, and effective time management.

Honors

Georgia Southern University President's List:

- Fall 2014, 2017
- Spring 2015, 2016, 2017, 2018

Scholarships

- Zell Miller & HOPE Scholarship
- Georgia Southern President's Scholarship

Georgia Southern University Dean's List

• Fall 2015, 2016

Awards

- Freshman Chemistry Award Spring 2015
- Outstanding Scholar Graduating Senior